<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<TeamMembers>
	<Person>
		<ID>0</ID>
		<Name>Mina Ryten</Name>
		<Title>Dr (MBBS, PhD)</Title>
		<Job>Professor of Clinical Genetics/Honorary Consultant in Clinical Genetics</Job>
		<Email>mina.ryten@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Transcriptomics; Data Analysis of High-throughput Techniques for complex neurological diseases; Data Analysis of High-throughput Techniques to improve the diagnostic yield for rare neurogenetic disorders</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Mina Ryten </b>is Professor of Clinical Genetics at UCL Great Ormond Street Institute of Child Health and is an Honorary Consultant in Clinical Genetics at Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children and at Guy’s Hospital. She is a clinician scientist with experience in both clinical and research settings. In her clinical practice she cares for individuals and families with, or at risk of, a range of conditions which may have a genetic basis. As well as providing a diagnosis, the aim of her clinics is to help individuals affected by a genetic disorder live as normally as possible with their condition. Mina’s research lab focuses on the use of transcriptomics, primarily derived from human brain, to improve the molecular understanding of complex and rare neurological disorders.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>mina.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Mina_Ryten</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>1</ID>
		<Name>Juan A. Botía</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Professor/Honorary Senior Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>j.botia@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Machine Learning; Algorithmic Design; Statistical Learning; Neuro-degeneration; Genetics of disease; Transcriptomics; Interplay between mendelian and complex diseases.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Juan A. Botía</b>, Phd. is Professor in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence at the University of Murcia, Murcia, Spain. He is also Honorary Senior Research Fellow at the Institute of Neurology, University College London, UK since July, 2017. Juan A. Botía is PhD in Computational Science and Artificial Intelligence(March 2002).He obtained a position at Universidad de Murcia as Reader in April 2009. His research interests include, from the very beginning of his career, multi - agent systems, distributed artificial intelligence and machine learning with an emphasis on applications of AI. He has been involved in research and innovation projects with a common aspect: applying AI and algorithm approaches to real life problems, including domains like agriculture, multi-media content recommendation, indoor location of mobile devices and ambient assisted living. During 2013 Dr.Botía moved to London to enjoy a sabbatical period with Dr.Juan C. Augusto at Middlesex University. In 2014 he joined the UKBEC project at King’s College London to work as Research Associate, in the Department of Molecular and Medical Genetics, School of Medicine under the supervision of Mike Weale and Mina Ryten. In 2015, within the same project, he was honoured to start working with John Hardy and Mina Ryten at the Department of Molecular Neuroscience, University College London, until mid 2017 when he returned to Universidad de Murcia. During his period at the UK, he started applying AI techniques to transcriptomics and genetics within the area of neurology, until now. CurrentMemberly, he is member of the Ryten Lab.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>botia.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>juanbot</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Juan_Botia</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>2</ID>
		<Name>Juan A. Sanchez</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>
			Associate Lecturer
		</Job>
		<Email>jlaguna@um.es</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Applying artificial intelligence, machine learning and data mining techniques to help MDs intepretate the aetiology of neurological diseases such as Alzheimer or Parkinson.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Juan A. Sánchez</b> is an Associate Professor in the Department of Communications and Information Engineering (DIIC) at the Computer Science Faculty, of the University of Murcia, Spain. He received a B.Sc. (1997), M.Sc. (1999) and Ph.D. (2006) degree in Computer Science from the University of Murcia.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>sanchez.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>drlaguna</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Juan_Sanchez23</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>3</ID>
		<Name>Karishma D'Sa</Name>
		<Title>MSc</Title>
		<Job>Research assistant/PhD student</Job>
		<Email>k.d'sa@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Transcriptomics; Genetics; Neurodegeneration; Bioinformatics; Personalized medicine.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Karishma</b>’s research focuses on the analysis of transcriptomic data with the aim of understanding how genetic variation affects gene expression in human brain using allele specific expression. She holds a Master’s degree in Bioinformatics from King’s College London.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>kd.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
		<ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>4</ID>
		<Name>Sebastian Guelfi</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Research Associate</Job>
		<Email>m.guelfi@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Genomics; Genetics; Bioinformatics; Novel transcription; Gene regulation; RNA Splicing; Neurodegeneration; Machine Learning;  Biostatistics, Data integration.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Sebastian Guelfi was a Postdoctoral Research Fellow in the Ryten Lab, where he studied RNA splicing by leveraging large genomic datasets. He obtained his PhD in bioinformatics at University College London where he integrated different forms of genomic data to investigate the relationship between gene regulation and neurodegenerative diseases. Before pursuing his interests in data analysis and health care, Sebastian worked for 6 years in the private sector designing and developing software to solve logistics problems.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>seb.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>SebGuelfi</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Sebastian_Guelfi</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>5</ID>
		<Name>Regina H. Reynolds</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>regina.reynolds.16@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Functional genomics; Neurodegeneration; Statistical Genetics; Transcriptomics.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Regina is a Postdoctoral Research Fellow working in the Ryten Lab at University College London. Her work uses transcriptomics to identify molecular signatures of Parkinson's disease progression.
			<br/>
			Regina's background is a blend of molecular biology and bioinformatics. She completed a BSc and MSc in Molecular Biomedicine at the University of Copenhagen, where she investigated the role of miR-34 and SIRT1 in Huntington's disease-affected tissues. In addition, she completed her PhD at University College London, where she explored the importance of cell-type-specific gene expression regulation and splicing in Parkinson’s disease.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>regina.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>RHReynolds</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Regina_Reynolds</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>6</ID>
		<Name>David Zhang</Name>
		<Title>MSc</Title>
		<Job>PhD Student</Job>
		<Email>david.zhang.12@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Transcriptomics; Genetics; Bioinformatics; Novel transcription; Molecular diagnosis; Neurodegeneration; Mendelian Disease; Machine Learning; Statistical Modelling.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>David Zhang</b> chose genetics because it allowed him to combine his practical enjoyment of computational analysis with his interest in human biology. His PhD is focussed on developing algorithms to improve the molecular diagnosis of Mendelian disease patients.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>david.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>dzhang32</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>David_Zhang98</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>7</ID>
		<Name>Sonia García Ruiz</Name>
		<Title>MSc</Title>
		<Job>PhD Student/Research Assistant</Job>
		<Email>s.ruiz@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>RNA Splicing; Transcriptomics; Novel transcription; Web Development; Artificial Intelligence; Machine Learning; Software Development.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Sonia García Ruiz is a PhD student and software developer at UCL. She completed her Bachelor’s in Computer Science at the University of Miguel Hernández (Spain) in 2014. After that, she accumulated 2 years of experience as a software and web developer, working with clients such as Microsoft and Deloitte. Nevertheless, in 2017 she decided to return to university and completed her master’s degree in Artificial Intelligence at the University of Murcia in 2018.
			<br/>
			In the Ryten lab, she is focused on finding the mechanisms underlying the alternative splicing in human cells, and how those different products may interfiere in human health. Additionally, she uses her knowledge of web development to help build analysis and visualisation tools for easier data interpretation.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>sonia.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>SoniaRuiz</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Sonia_Garcia_Ruiz</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>8</ID>
		<Name>Zhongbo Chen</Name>
		<Title>MA BMBCh MRCP</Title>
		<Job>PhD Student/Clinical Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>zhongbo.chen@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Genetics; Neurodegenerative diseases; Clinical Neurology; Bioinformatics.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Zhongbo is a neurology registrar and PhD student on the UCL Leonard Wolfson Programme. Her project uses bioinformatic and machine learning techniques to study the genetics of neurodegenerative diseases. Alongside the PhD, she also practises in the Queen Square Neurogenetics clinic, developing specialist clinical experience in this field.
			<br/>
			Zhongbo's research interests started during her undergraduate degree in Physiology and Neuroscience at the University of Cambridge, where she studied the electrophysiology of skeletal muscle using microelectrodes for her final year project. She then completed her clinical training, qualifying as a doctor in 2010 from the University of Oxford. Before embarking on the PhD, she was a specialist registrar at the National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery and NIHR Neurology academic clinical fellow at King's College London.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>zhongbo.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>ZhongboUCL</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Zhongbo_Chen</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>9</ID>
		<Name>Siddharth Sethi</Name>
		<Title>MSc, PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>siddharth.sethi@astx.com</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Transcriptomics; UTRs; MicroRNAs; Enhancers; Regulatory domains; Chromatin interactions; 3D genome; Big data analysis; Machine learning; Statistical modelling; Data visualisation.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Siddharth Sethi</b> is a joint Postdoctoral Research Fellow between Ryten lab and Astex Pharmaceuticals in Cambridge. His research focuses on alternate 3’UTR mediated regulation in neurodegenerative disorders. Siddharth completed his graduation in Bio-technology in India and moved to the UK to pursue MSc in Bioinformatics from the University of Leicester. Soon after that he joined Mallon lab at MRC Harwell Institute as a Bioinformatics scientist, where he worked on several different projects before starting his PhD. He developed a deep interest in the functional properties of the non-coding part of the genome and focused his PhD research on deciphering regulatory networks and their impact on mouse phenotypes.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>sethi.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>sid-sethi</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>10</ID>
		<Name>Aine Fairbrother-Browne</Name>
		<Title>BSc, MSc</Title>
		<Job>PhD student</Job>
		<Email>aine.fairbrother-browne.18@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Neurodegenerative disease, medical genetics, bioinformatics.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Aine Fairbrother-Browne</b> is a BBSRC funded LIDo PhD student in both the Ryten lab at UCL and the Hodgkinson Medical and Molecular Genetics lab at King’s. She completed at BSc in Biology at Bristol University (2016), and then did an MSc in Bioinformatics and Systems Biology at Birkbeck (2017). In 2018 she started on the BBSRC funded LIDo PhD programme. Whilst working with Mina Ryten and Alan Hodgkinson, she is focused on nuclear regulation of the mitochondrial genome in brain and its role in age-related pathologies.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>aine.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>ainefairbrother</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>

	<Person>
		<ID>11</ID>
		<Name>Ana Luisa Gil Martínez</Name>
		<Title>MSc, PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>analuisagilm@gmail.com</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Functional genomics, neurodegeneration, neuroinflammation, statistical genetics, transcriptomics.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Ana Luisa Gil Martinez is a Postdoctoral Research Fellow at the Ryten lab. She completed her Bachelor's in Biochemistry (2010-2014) and her Master's Degree in Molecular Biology and Biotechnology (2014-2015) at the University of Murcia (Spain). During this time, she specialized in the study of inorganic compounds in nanoparticles for therapeutic purposes. After that, she was selected for a PhD position in the Clinical and Experimental Neuroscience Group. Her thesis was focused on the study of the involvement of glial cells in the neurodegenerative processes associated with Parkinsonism and aging. In 2019, she obtained a Double Doctor's degree by the University of Murcia (Spain) and Maastricht University (The Netherlands).
			<br/>
			Her postdoctoral project at the Ryten Lab aims to integrate co-expression models to investigate molecular mechanisms driving the progression of Parkinson's disease.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>analuisa.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Ana_Luisa_Gil_Martinez</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>12</ID>
		<Name>Emil Gustavsson</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>e.gustavsson@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Genetics; Neurodegenerative diseases; Bioinformatics; Genetic analysis to improve the diagnostic yield for neurological disorders.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Emil is a Postdoctoral Research Fellow in the Ryten lab at University College London. Emil completed his BSc and MSc in molecular genetics at Uppsala University. During this time, he worked on the influence of mtDNA variability on behaviour as well as the role of genetic variability of a vesicular monoaminergic associated transporter in addiction. For his PhD training Emil moved to Canada (University of British Columbia) to work on the molecular genetics of Parkinson’s and neurological diseases. His work mainly related to the identification of genes and how genetic variability influences the penetrance and progression of disease. Emil joined the Ryten lab in early 2020 and his aims to investigate the role of recursive splicing on previously identified novel expressed regions and using long-read sequencing techniques to define the expression of novel transcripts of genes involved in neurological disease.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>emil.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Emil_Gustavsson</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>13</ID>
		<Name>Fran Kiernan</Name>
		<Title>MSc</Title>
		<Job>Research assistant</Job>
		<Email>f.kiernan@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Clinical genetics; Genomics; Transcriptomics; RNA-seq; Neurodegenerative diseases; Long-read sequencing.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Fran Kiernan completed an MSc in Genomic Medicine at King's College London and St. George's, University of London in 2019. In the RytenLab, he focused on novel exon discovery and validation in genes associated with neurodegenerative diseases using a combination of wet-lab and dry-lab techniques, including RNA-sequencing on Sanger and nanopore (MinIon) technologies.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>fran.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>FranKiernan</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Fran_Kiernan</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>14</ID>
		<Name>Amy Hicks</Name>
		<Title>BSc</Title>
		<Job>PhD Student</Job>
		<Email>amy.hicks.19@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Parkinson’s disease, mitochondrial dysfunction, gene regulatory mechanisms.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Amy is a first year PhD student at UCL. She completed her Bachelor’s in Neuroscience at the University of Leeds in 2019, during which she completed an industrial placement year at Eisai Ltd in Hatfield. In 2020 she began a joint PhD project between the Ryten and Plun-Favreau labs, examining the gene regulatory networks underlying mitophagy modulation and other Parkinson’s disease related pathways.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>amy.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>amyrosehicks</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Amy_Hicks7</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>15</ID>
		<Name>Federica Merella</Name>
		<Title>Dr</Title>
		<Job>MSc student</Job>
		<Email>merellafede@gmail.com</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Personalised medicine, genomic, paediatric pain.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Dr Federica Merella is a consultant paediatric anaesthetist the Birmingham Children's Hospital, UK. She is a strong advocate for the use of paediatric regional anaesthesia ultrasound guided as opioid sparing pain management technique in children. Her interest in research in pain, stratified medicine and genomics motivated her to return to university, UCL, where she is completing the MSc in Cell and Gene therapy. She has recently joined the Ryten lab as MSc student where, she is learning the bioinformatic foundations of gene expression analysis. Under the supervision of Ana Luisa Gil and professor Mina Ryten, is looking at possible identification of gene co-expression networks distinctive for Parkinson disease progression.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>federica.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Federica-Merella</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>16</ID>
		<Name>Aaron Wagen</Name>
		<Title>MBBS/BA, FRACP, MPhil (Medicine)</Title>
		<Job>PhD Student/ Clinical Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>a.wagen@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Neurodegeneration, Transcriptomics, Clinical Neurology, Computational biology.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Aaron is a neurology trainee undertaking a PhD in the Wolfson-Eisai PhD Programme in Neurodegeneration. His project is exploring the spatial transcriptomics of Parkinson's disease. He undertook his medical training in Australia, completing an MPhil at the University of Melbourne using mass spectrometry to explore amyloid beta in Alzheimer disease. He moved to the UK to complete his clinical training at the National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery, and worked as a clinical research fellow at the Dementia Research Centre before commencing his PhD.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>aaron.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>aaronwagen</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Aaron-Wagen</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>17</ID>
		<Name>Kylie Montgomery</Name>
		<Title></Title>
		<Job>Research Assistant</Job>
		<Email>kylie.montgomery@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>
			Genetics, neurodevelopment, rare disease, transcriptomics, novel therapies.
		</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Kylie studied biomedical science at Victoria University of Wellington, Te Herenga Waka, and has more recently completed her MSc at King’s College London. 
			She has over 15 years of experience in molecular genetics, predominantly in prenatal diagnosis, and has attained HCPC registration as a clinical scientist in genetics. 
			Her research experience includes contributing to the 100,000 genomes project and working in translational genetics. She is particularly interested in the overlaps between neurodevelopmental and neurodegenerative diseases as well as the development of novel therapies for rare diseases. 
			Kylie is currently a research assistant in the Ryten lab at UCL. Her focus is on long-read sequencing methods and analysis and will be starting a PhD exploring gene expression during neurodevelopment.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>kylie.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>KylieMontgomery</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Kylie-Montgomery-2</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	
	<Pet>
		<ID>18</ID>
		<Name>Ted</Name>
		<Nickname>Boof</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Kylie</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>ted.png</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Ted is a rehomed Newfie that loves chasing birds, demanding treats, and being the centre of attention. Ted specialises in using his big brown eyes and raising his expressive eyebrows to get his way.
		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Pet>
		<ID>19</ID>
		<Name>Lola</Name>
		<Nickname>Tita</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Sonia</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>tita.jpg</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Lola was a 15 years-old lady that unfortunately passed away at the beginning of 2022. She was really one of a kind; loyal, friendly and able to understand so many different Spanish words and human emotions that inevitably converted her into an irreplaceable member of our family.
			Although she was completely deaf at the moment of her death, she enjoyed an impressive overall fitness throughout all her life. She also had such an amazing charisma that made all our (both human and four-leggy) neighbours wanted to know her more while enjoying with her presence.
			She will be very much missed for the years to come and will always occupy a special place in our hearts. We'll always love you Tita and will never forget you!
		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Pet>
		<ID>20</ID>
		<Name>Suka</Name>
		<Nickname>Suki</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Sonia</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>suki.jpg</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Suki is an almost 5 years-old tiny black cat that was born with a bone developmental issue. 
			Although she is completely fine now and enjoys a very happy life, her health issue provided her with a small stature and baby appearance that doesn't help Sonia to consider her like a proper grown and independent adult :).
			She is a cuddly, kids-friendly, eager-to-please, loving and purrfect cat (although many members of Sonia's family may disagree with some of these adjectives) and she is very much loved in our family (we all agree on this).

		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Pet>
		<ID>21</ID>
		<Name>Oliver and Pippi</Name>
		<Nickname>Olly, The Pipster</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Regina (and Laura)</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>oliver.jpg</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Oliver (the fluffy one) and Pippi (the moustached one) started their lives as two feral cats on the streets of Tottenham. While they remain firm supporters of the Tottenham Spurs, they gave up their feral ways when they adopted their humans. Both love a good chin scratch, playing fetch, and challenging their humans’ pre-conceptions of what cats eat (olives are a particular favourite).
		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Person>
		<ID>22</ID>
		<Name>Savita Nutan</Name>
		<Title>MSc, DipRCPath</Title>
		<Job>Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>s.nutan@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>
			Transcriptomics, Neurometabolic disease, Rare Disease, Genomics.
		</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Savita is a research fellow working on improving the genetic diagnosis of patients with suspected neurometabolic disease through the application of transcriptomic technologies and interpretation of whole exome- and whole genome data. Savita is registered with the UK Health and Care Professions Council as a Clinical Scientist and has worked for Great Ormond Street hospital (2018-2022) where she helped deliver the return of 100,000 genomes project results and run the non-invasive prenatal diagnosis service. She is a Diplomate of the Royal College of Pathology. Prior to this she worked as a trainee healthcare scientist at Nottingham University Hospitals Trust where she obtained her MSc in Clinical Sciences (Clinical Genetics), and previously worked as a genetic technologist at Bristol Genetics Laboratory.
			Savita obtained a Molecular Genetics BSc and a Biomedical and Molecular Sciences MSc from King’s College London.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>savita.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>savitanutan</GitHub>
		<ResearchGate>Savita-Nutan-2</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
</TeamMembers>