<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<TeamMembers>
	<Person>
		<ID>0</ID>
		<Name>Mina Ryten</Name>
		<Title>Prof (MBBS, PhD)</Title>
		<Job>UK DRI Cambridge Centre Director/Professor of Clinical Genetics</Job>
		<Email>mr2022@medschl.cam.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Transcriptomics; Data Analysis of High-throughput Techniques for complex neurological diseases; Data Analysis of High-throughput Techniques to improve the diagnostic yield for rare neurogenetic disorders</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Professor Mina Ryten is a clinician scientist with a long-standing interest in using human brain transcriptomics to understand neurological diseases. Mina began her medical training at Cambridge University and completed an MB PhD at UCL. While her PhD focused on purinergic signalling in skeletal muscle development, she subsequently trained in bioinformatics through an MRC Post-doctoral Fellowship in Systems Biology. This experience led her to become a Clinical Geneticist, shaped her research interests and formed the basis of her application for an MRC Clinician Scientist Fellowship. Since 2017 Mina has led her own research group at the UCL Institute of Neurology, and later the UCL Great Ormond Street Institute of Child Health. She also worked as an Honorary Consultant in Clinical Genetics at Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children and Guy’s Hospital. During her clinical practice, she cared for individuals and families with - or at risk of - a range of conditions with a potential genetic basis, helping them to get a diagnosis and to live their lives as normally as possible with their condition. In January 2024 Mina’s lab moved to Cambridge University, where she became the Director of the UK DRI at Cambridge. At the core of her group’s research is using human brain transcriptomic data as a genome-wide functional read-out of an individual’s DNA, which can inform our understanding of the genetic origins of neurodegenerative diseases. In the context of rare neurogenetic diseases, this has meant using correlations in transcriptomic data to identify hidden gene-to-gene relationships amongst Mendelian genes. In the context of complex neurological diseases, this has meant to generate and use regulatory data across the human brain to link disease risk positions to specific genes. Thus, over the last ten years, she has developed extensive expertise in generating and using human brain transcriptomic data with a specific focus on neurodegenerative diseases, particularly Lewy body disorders.

		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>mina.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
		<GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Mina_Ryten</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<!--<Person>
		<ID>1</ID>
		<Name>Juan A. Botía</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Professor/Honorary Senior Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>j.botia@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Machine Learning; Algorithmic Design; Statistical Learning; Neuro-degeneration; Genetics of disease; Transcriptomics; Interplay between mendelian and complex diseases.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Juan A. Botía</b>, Phd. is Professor in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence at the University of Murcia, Murcia, Spain. He is also Honorary Senior Research Fellow at the Institute of Neurology, University College London, UK since July, 2017. Juan A. Botía is PhD in Computational Science and Artificial Intelligence(March 2002).He obtained a position at Universidad de Murcia as Reader in April 2009. His research interests include, from the very beginning of his career, multi - agent systems, distributed artificial intelligence and machine learning with an emphasis on applications of AI. He has been involved in research and innovation projects with a common aspect: applying AI and algorithm approaches to real life problems, including domains like agriculture, multi-media content recommendation, indoor location of mobile devices and ambient assisted living. During 2013 Dr.Botía moved to London to enjoy a sabbatical period with Dr.Juan C. Augusto at Middlesex University. In 2014 he joined the UKBEC project at King’s College London to work as Research Associate, in the Department of Molecular and Medical Genetics, School of Medicine under the supervision of Mike Weale and Mina Ryten. In 2015, within the same project, he was honoured to start working with John Hardy and Mina Ryten at the Department of Molecular Neuroscience, University College London, until mid 2017 when he returned to Universidad de Murcia. During his period at the UK, he started applying AI techniques to transcriptomics and genetics within the area of neurology, until now. CurrentMemberly, he is member of the Ryten Lab.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>botia.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>juanbot</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Juan_Botia</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>-->
	<!--<Person>
		<ID>2</ID>
		<Name>Juan A. Sanchez</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>
			Associate Lecturer
		</Job>
		<Email>jlaguna@um.es</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Applying artificial intelligence, machine learning and data mining techniques to help MDs intepretate the aetiology of neurological diseases such as Alzheimer or Parkinson.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Juan A. Sánchez</b> is an Associate Professor in the Department of Communications and Information Engineering (DIIC) at the Computer Science Faculty, of the University of Murcia, Spain. He received a B.Sc. (1997), M.Sc. (1999) and Ph.D. (2006) degree in Computer Science from the University of Murcia.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>sanchez.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>drlaguna</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Juan_Sanchez23</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>-->
	<Person>
		<ID>3</ID>
		<Name>Karishma D'Sa</Name>
		<Title>MSc</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>k.d'sa@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Transcriptomics; Genetics; Neurodegeneration; Bioinformatics; Personalized medicine.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Karishma</b>’s research focuses on the analysis of transcriptomic data with the aim of understanding how genetic variation affects gene expression in human brain using allele specific expression. She holds a Master’s degree in Bioinformatics from King’s College London.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>kd.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
		<GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>4</ID>
		<Name>Sebastian Guelfi</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Research Associate</Job>
		<Email>m.guelfi@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Genomics; Genetics; Bioinformatics; Novel transcription; Gene regulation; RNA Splicing; Neurodegeneration; Machine Learning;  Biostatistics, Data integration.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Sebastian Guelfi was a Postdoctoral Research Fellow in the Ryten Lab, where he studied RNA splicing by leveraging large genomic datasets. He obtained his PhD in bioinformatics at University College London where he integrated different forms of genomic data to investigate the relationship between gene regulation and neurodegenerative diseases. Before pursuing his interests in data analysis and health care, Sebastian worked for 6 years in the private sector designing and developing software to solve logistics problems.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>seb.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>SebGuelfi</GitHub>
		<GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Sebastian_Guelfi</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>5</ID>
		<Name>Regina H. Reynolds</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>regina.reynolds.16@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Functional genomics; Neurodegeneration; Statistical Genetics; Transcriptomics.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Regina is a Postdoctoral Research Fellow working in the Ryten Lab at University College London. Her work uses transcriptomics to identify molecular signatures of Parkinson's disease progression.
			<br/>
			Regina's background is a blend of molecular biology and bioinformatics. She completed a BSc and MSc in Molecular Biomedicine at the University of Copenhagen, where she investigated the role of miR-34 and SIRT1 in Huntington's disease-affected tissues. In addition, she completed her PhD at University College London, where she explored the importance of cell-type-specific gene expression regulation and splicing in Parkinson’s disease.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>regina.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>RHReynolds</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Regina_Reynolds</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>6</ID>
		<Name>David Zhang</Name>
		<Title>MSc</Title>
		<Job>PhD Student</Job>
		<Email>david.zhang.12@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Transcriptomics; Genetics; Bioinformatics; Novel transcription; Molecular diagnosis; Neurodegeneration; Mendelian Disease; Machine Learning; Statistical Modelling.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>David Zhang</b> chose genetics because it allowed him to combine his practical enjoyment of computational analysis with his interest in human biology. His PhD is focussed on developing algorithms to improve the molecular diagnosis of Mendelian disease patients.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>david.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>dzhang32</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>David_Zhang98</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>7</ID>
		<Name>Sonia García-Ruiz</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>s.ruiz@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>RNA Splicing; Transcriptomics; Short-Read RNA sequencing data; Long-Read RNA sequencing data; Novel transcription; Web Development; Software Development.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
      Sonia García Ruiz is a Postdoctoral Research Fellow working in the Ryten Lab at University College London . She completed her BSc in Computer Science at the University of Miguel Hernández (Spain) in 2014 with a first class degree, after which she became a software and web developer, accumulating over 2 years of experience working with international clients such as Microsoft and Deloitte across multiple countries. In 2017, she decided to return to academia and completed her MSc in Artificial Intelligence at the University of Murcia (with distinction). The exposure to genomic medicine over the course of her MSc led her  to move to London in 2018 to work in the Ryten Lab as a Research Assistant, and her decision a year later to embark on a part-time PhD. Sonia completed her PhD on splicing accuracy across human introns, tissues and ageing in 2023.
      <br/>
      Currently, Sonia is interested in combining short- and long-read RNA-sequencing data to understand transcriptional accuracy in dementia across cell types.
    </Biography>
		<ImagePath>sonia.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>SoniaRuiz</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar>soniagruiz</GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Sonia_Garcia_Ruiz</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>8</ID>
		<Name>Zhongbo Chen</Name>
		<Title>MA BMBCh MRCP PhD</Title>
		<Job>Crick Postdoctoral Clinical Research Fellow / Neurology Registrar</Job>
		<Email>zhongbo.chen@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Genetics; Neurodegenerative diseases; Clinical Neurology; Bioinformatics.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
      I am a research fellow on the Crick clinical postdoctoral programme. My research focuses on using transcriptomics to improve understanding of neurogenetic and neurodegenerative diseases. Currently, I am based in the labs of Professor Mina Ryten and Professor Sonia Gandhi, using longitudinal RNA-sequencing data to understand progression and post-transcriptional mechanisms in neurodegenerative diseases, namely in Parkinson's disease and hereditary ataxia. I am also a neurology registrar at the National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery. I completed my PhD on the Leonard Wolfson Programme for Neurodegeneration at UCL. My project used bioinformatic and machine learning techniques to study the genetics of neurodegenerative diseases through functional genomic annotation and RNA-sequencing. My research interests started during my intercalated undergraduate degree in Physiology and Neuroscience at the University of Cambridge, where I studied the electrophysiology of skeletal muscle using microelectrodes. I then completed clinical training at the University of Oxford. Following this, I was an academic medicine foundation doctor at Imperial College London. Before embarking on the PhD, I was a specialist registrar and NIHR Neurology academic clinical fellow at King's College London.
    </Biography>
		<ImagePath>zhongbo.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>ZhongboUCL</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Zhongbo_Chen</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>9</ID>
		<Name>Siddharth Sethi</Name>
		<Title>MSc, PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>siddharth.sethi@astx.com</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Transcriptomics; UTRs; MicroRNAs; Enhancers; Regulatory domains; Chromatin interactions; 3D genome; Big data analysis; Machine learning; Statistical modelling; Data visualisation.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Siddharth Sethi</b> is a joint Postdoctoral Research Fellow between Ryten lab and Astex Pharmaceuticals in Cambridge. His research focuses on alternate 3’UTR mediated regulation in neurodegenerative disorders. Siddharth completed his graduation in Bio-technology in India and moved to the UK to pursue MSc in Bioinformatics from the University of Leicester. Soon after that he joined Mallon lab at MRC Harwell Institute as a Bioinformatics scientist, where he worked on several different projects before starting his PhD. He developed a deep interest in the functional properties of the non-coding part of the genome and focused his PhD research on deciphering regulatory networks and their impact on mouse phenotypes.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>sethi.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>sid-sethi</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>10</ID>
		<Name>Aine Fairbrother-Browne</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>aine.fairbrother-browne.18@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Neurodegenerative disease, medical genetics, bioinformatics.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			<b>Aine Fairbrother-Browne</b> completed her BBSRC funded LIDo PhD joined program at UCL and King's in 2023. She completed at BSc in Biology at Bristol University (2016), and then did an MSc in Bioinformatics and Systems Biology at Birkbeck (2017). In 2018 she started on the BBSRC funded LIDo PhD programme. Whilst working with Mina Ryten and Alan Hodgkinson, she is focused on nuclear regulation of the mitochondrial genome in brain and its role in age-related pathologies.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>aine.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>ainefairbrother</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>

	<Person>
		<ID>11</ID>
		<Name>Ana Luisa Gil Martínez</Name>
		<Title>MSc, PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>analuisagilm@gmail.com</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Functional genomics, neurodegeneration, neuroinflammation, statistical genetics, transcriptomics.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Ana Luisa Gil Martinez is a Postdoctoral Research Fellow at the Ryten lab. She completed her Bachelor's in Biochemistry (2010-2014) and her Master's Degree in Molecular Biology and Biotechnology (2014-2015) at the University of Murcia (Spain). During this time, she specialized in the study of inorganic compounds in nanoparticles for therapeutic purposes. After that, she was selected for a PhD position in the Clinical and Experimental Neuroscience Group. Her thesis was focused on the study of the involvement of glial cells in the neurodegenerative processes associated with Parkinsonism and aging. In 2019, she obtained a Double Doctor's degree by the University of Murcia (Spain) and Maastricht University (The Netherlands).
			<br/>
			Her postdoctoral project at the Ryten Lab aims to integrate co-expression models to investigate molecular mechanisms driving the progression of Parkinson's disease.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>analuisa.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Ana_Luisa_Gil_Martinez</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>12</ID>
		<Name>Emil Gustavsson</Name>
		<Title>PhD</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>e.gustavsson@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Genetics; Neurodegenerative diseases; Bioinformatics; Genetic analysis to improve the diagnostic yield for neurological disorders.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Emil is a Postdoctoral Research Fellow in the Ryten lab at University College London. Emil completed his BSc and MSc in molecular genetics at Uppsala University. During this time, he worked on the influence of mtDNA variability on behaviour as well as the role of genetic variability of a vesicular monoaminergic associated transporter in addiction. For his PhD training Emil moved to Canada (University of British Columbia) to work on the molecular genetics of Parkinson’s and neurological diseases. His work mainly related to the identification of genes and how genetic variability influences the penetrance and progression of disease. Emil joined the Ryten lab in early 2020 and his aims to investigate the role of recursive splicing on previously identified novel expressed regions and using long-read sequencing techniques to define the expression of novel transcripts of genes involved in neurological disease.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>emil.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>egustavsson</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar>emilkgustavsson</GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Emil_Gustavsson</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>13</ID>
		<Name>Fran Kiernan</Name>
		<Title>MSc</Title>
		<Job>Research assistant</Job>
		<Email>f.kiernan@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Clinical genetics; Genomics; Transcriptomics; RNA-seq; Neurodegenerative diseases; Long-read sequencing.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Fran Kiernan completed an MSc in Genomic Medicine at King's College London and St. George's, University of London in 2019. In the RytenLab, he focused on novel exon discovery and validation in genes associated with neurodegenerative diseases using a combination of wet-lab and dry-lab techniques, including RNA-sequencing on Sanger and nanopore (MinIon) technologies.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>fran.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>FranKiernan</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Fran_Kiernan</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>14</ID>
		<Name>Amy Hicks</Name>
		<Title>Dr</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>amy.hicks.19@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Gene regulatory mechanisms in Parkinson’s disease.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Amy studied Neuroscience at the University of Leeds before starting a Wolfson-Eisai PhD studentship in Neurodegeneration in 2019, co-supervised by Professors Mina Ryten and Helene Plun-Favreau at UCL. Amy is currently undertaking a postdoctoral research fellow position studying transcriptomic features in Parkinson’s disease patients.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>amy.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>amyrosehicks</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Amy_Hicks7</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>15</ID>
		<Name>Federica Merella</Name>
		<Title>Dr</Title>
		<Job>MSc student</Job>
		<Email>merellafede@gmail.com</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Personalised medicine, genomic, paediatric pain.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Dr Federica Merella is a consultant paediatric anaesthetist the Birmingham Children's Hospital, UK. She is a strong advocate for the use of paediatric regional anaesthesia ultrasound guided as opioid sparing pain management technique in children. Her interest in research in pain, stratified medicine and genomics motivated her to return to university, UCL, where she is completing the MSc in Cell and Gene therapy. She has recently joined the Ryten lab as MSc student where, she is learning the bioinformatic foundations of gene expression analysis. Under the supervision of Ana Luisa Gil and professor Mina Ryten, is looking at possible identification of gene co-expression networks distinctive for Parkinson disease progression.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>federica.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub></GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Federica-Merella</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>16</ID>
		<Name>Aaron Wagen</Name>
		<Title>MBBS/BA, FRACP, MPhil (Medicine)</Title>
		<Job>PhD Student/ Clinical Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>a.wagen@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>Neurodegeneration, Transcriptomics, Clinical Neurology, Computational biology.</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Aaron is a neurology trainee undertaking a PhD in the Wolfson-Eisai PhD Programme in Neurodegeneration. His project is exploring the spatial transcriptomics of Parkinson's disease. He undertook his medical training in Australia, completing an MPhil at the University of Melbourne using mass spectrometry to explore amyloid beta in Alzheimer disease. He moved to the UK to complete his clinical training at the National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery, and worked as a clinical research fellow at the Dementia Research Centre before commencing his PhD.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>aaron.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>aaronwagen</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Aaron-Wagen</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Person>
		<ID>17</ID>
		<Name>Kylie Montgomery</Name>
		<Title></Title>
		<Job>Research Assistant</Job>
		<Email>kylie.montgomery@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>
			Genetics, neurodevelopment, rare disease, transcriptomics, novel therapies.
		</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Kylie studied biomedical science at Victoria University of Wellington, Te Herenga Waka, and has more recently completed her MSc at King’s College London. 
			She has over 15 years of experience in molecular genetics, predominantly in prenatal diagnosis, and has attained HCPC registration as a clinical scientist in genetics. 
			<br/>
			Her research experience includes contributing to the 100,000 genomes project and working in translational genetics. She is particularly interested in the overlaps between neurodevelopmental and neurodegenerative diseases as well as the development of novel therapies for rare diseases. 
			Kylie is currently a research assistant in the Ryten lab at UCL. Her focus is on long-read sequencing methods and analysis and will be starting a PhD exploring gene expression during neurodevelopment.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>kylie.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>KylieMontgomery</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Kylie-Montgomery-2</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	
	<Pet>
		<ID>18</ID>
		<Name>Ted</Name>
		<Nickname>Boof</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Kylie</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>ted.png</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Ted is a rehomed Newfie that loves chasing birds, demanding treats, and being the centre of attention. Ted specialises in using his big brown eyes and raising his expressive eyebrows to get his way.
		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Pet>
		<ID>19</ID>
		<Name>Lola</Name>
		<Nickname>Tita</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Sonia</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>tita.jpg</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Lola was a 15 years-old lady that unfortunately passed away at the beginning of 2022. She was really one of a kind; loyal, friendly and able to understand so many different Spanish words and human emotions that inevitably converted her into an irreplaceable member of our family.
			Although she was completely deaf at the moment of her death, she enjoyed an impressive overall good health throughout all her life. She also had such an amazing charisma that made all our neighbours wanted to know her more while enjoying with her presence.
			She will be very much missed for the years to come and will always occupy a special place in our hearts. We'll always love you, Tita, and will never forget you!
		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Pet>
		<ID>20</ID>
		<Name>Suki</Name>
		<Nickname>Sukiti</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Sonia</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>suki.jpg</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Suki is an almost 5 years-old tiny black cat that was born with a bone developmental issue.
			Although she is completely fine now and enjoys a very happy life, her health issue provided her with a small stature and baby appearance that doesn't help Sonia at all to consider her like the proper grown and independent adult that she is :).
			She is a cuddly, kids-friendly, eager-to-please, loving and purrfect cat (although many members of Sonia's family may disagree with the 'kids-friendly' and 'eager-to-please' adjectives) and she is very much loved in our family (we all agree on this).

		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Pet>
		<ID>21</ID>
		<Name>Oliver and Pippi</Name>
		<Nickname>Olly, The Pipster</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Regina (and Laura)</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>oliver.jpg</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Oliver (the fluffy one) and Pippi (the moustached one) started their lives as two feral cats on the streets of Tottenham. While they remain firm supporters of the Tottenham Spurs, they gave up their feral ways when they adopted their humans. Both love a good chin scratch, playing fetch, and challenging their humans’ pre-conceptions of what cats eat (olives are a particular favourite).
		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Person>
		<ID>22</ID>
		<Name>Savita Nutan</Name>
		<Title>MSc, DipRCPath</Title>
		<Job>Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>s.nutan@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>
			Transcriptomics, Neurometabolic disease, Rare Disease, Genomics.
		</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Savita is a research fellow working on improving the genetic diagnosis of patients with suspected neurometabolic disease through the application of transcriptomic technologies and interpretation of whole exome- and whole genome data. Savita is registered with the UK Health and Care Professions Council as a Clinical Scientist and has worked for Great Ormond Street hospital (2018-2022) where she helped deliver the return of 100,000 genomes project results and run the non-invasive prenatal diagnosis service. She is a Diplomate of the Royal College of Pathology. Prior to this she worked as a trainee healthcare scientist at Nottingham University Hospitals Trust where she obtained her MSc in Clinical Sciences (Clinical Genetics), and previously worked as a genetic technologist at Bristol Genetics Laboratory.
			Savita obtained a Molecular Genetics BSc and a Biomedical and Molecular Sciences MSc from King’s College London.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>savita.jpg</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>savitanutan</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Savita-Nutan-2</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
	<Pet>
		<ID>22</ID>
		<Name>Rocky</Name>
		<Nickname>Rocky</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Mina</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>rocky.jpg</ImagePath>
		<Bio> 
			My name is Rocky. I was born high in the Welsh hills. My father was Farmer Ray's poodle Boris. If you visited the farm, dad would greet you at the gates, and he would look you up and down to see if you were alright. He taught my brother Max and I everything you need to know about life in the country. Then I came to live with Mina and her family in Cambridge, and all in all I think life here is swell.
			<br/>
			I have lots of jobs around the house. I am the family guard, and if anyone comes to the door, I look them up and down just like I was taught.  If they're mean they better watch out. If they're kind, well, they can have snuggles. My big brother does not like to wash his face, so every morning I have to clean it with kisses. After breakfast I sit with my sister on the sofa during cello practice to count time for her. I have to attend lots of meetings with Mina; after all, I am her right hand man, and so I have a special seat beside her in the boardroom. Funny, she also sleeps there... 
			<br/>
			Every day, I patrol the floorboards for rats; if they're underneath I scare them out and I hunt them down. Once, I drowned a big one. I caught a crow last year, and we had to sprint home when its brothers started to dive bomb us. Then I learnt to track hare, they're fast but if you stick with them,  you can drive them into the hedgerow and finish them off. Where we live you can find muntjac. They're fun to chase, but I never mean them any harm. I once found a trapped one and I  helped save it. I like other sports too. Fetch is fun but I still can't catch a ball in my mouth, I've climbed a munro in Scotland, I'm happy to challenge a whippet to a sprint or an alsatian to spar. I don't usually win, but I've never once shamed my family name! 
			<br/>
			I am quiet, kind, but I am a proud cockapoo and for good reason. I know many tricks like roll over, shake paw, hide and seek, naming toys, sniffing out hidden snacks, and even playing piano. I don't have an achilles heel, but some say I do have an achilles tummy. I just love bread, meat, smelly fish and cheese, and more than anything, peanut butter. If you leave some lying around, I apologise in advance, but I simply won't resist.
		</Bio>
	</Pet>
	<Pet>
		<ID>23</ID>
		<Name>Maki and Nori</Name>
		<Nickname>Maki and Nori</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Aine</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>maki.jpg</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			Likes: each other, drinking water from a human’s water glass, avocado, banana, marmite, Amazon cardboard package strips, anything that’s not an expensive cat toy specially purchased for them.<br/>
			Dislikes: The evil vacuum and even more evil blender.
		</Bio>
	</Pet>
  <Pet>
    <ID>24</ID>
    <Name>Pumpkin</Name>
    <Nickname>Pancake, Punkeg, Kitty</Nickname>
    <HumanName>Amy (and Adam)</HumanName>
    <ImagePath>pumpkin.png</ImagePath>
    <Bio>
      Pumpkin was rescued as a young pregnant stray and brought to live with a fosterer in Barnet along with 4 other cats (+ another four once her kittens were born), several guinea pigs, rats and a bearded dragon. She was keen to get away from the zoo house and once she found a forever home just next door, she settled into regular zoomies, destroying spider plants and waking her humans up at 5am. One day she hopes to finally catch her tail, she’s getting closer every day.
    </Bio>
  </Pet>
	<Person>
		<ID>25</ID>
		<Name>Melissa Grant-Peters</Name>
		<Title>DPhil</Title>
		<Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
		<Email>m.grant-peters@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>
			Neurodegenerative disorders; molecular neuroscience; high resolution and high throughput molecular profiling methods; interdisciplinary approaches to neuroscience; cross-modality and cross-disease integrative analysis
		</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
			Melissa is currently a postdoctoral research fellow in the Ryten lab at University College London. Her current project focuses on understanding the changes to cellular architecture in the context of Parkinson’s disease by using a combination of single cell and spatially resolved transcriptomic data.
      Her scientific background is quite broad, having studied a BSc in interdisciplinary science and technology (Federal University of São Paulo) and subsequently specialising in neuroscience with an MSc (University College Cork). She returned to her interdisciplinary interests for her doctoral studies in the Dendrou lab (University of Oxford), where she used an integrative approach to profile the spatially resolved molecular landscape of the human central nervous system.
		</Biography>
		<ImagePath>melissa.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>mgrantpeters</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Melissa-Grant-Peters</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
  <Person>
		<ID>26</ID>
		<Name>Rhys Dore</Name>
		<Title>Dr [BA BMBCh MSc MRCPCH]</Title>
		<Job>Academic Clinical Fellow</Job>
		<Email>rhys.dore.20@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
		<ResearchInterest>
			Research Interests: Clinical Genetics, Clinical Paediatrics, Bioinformatics, Rare Disease
		</ResearchInterest>
		<Biography>
      Rhys is a clinical genetics registrar and an NIHR Academic Clinical Fellow (Clinical Genetics) at the Maurice Wohl Clinical Neuroscience Institute, King’s College London with the Ule lab (UK DRI). He completed his intercalated degree (major: neuroscience, 2015) and clinical training (2018) at the University of Oxford, and an MSc in Paediatrics and Child Health at UCL (2022). He undertook the Academic Foundation Programme in Brighton before completing junior paediatric training in London and an NIHR Academic Clinical Fellowship (Paediatrics) with the Ryten lab.
    </Biography>
		<ImagePath>rhys.png</ImagePath>
		<GitHub>rhysdore</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
		<ResearchGate>Rhys-Dore-2</ResearchGate>
		<CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
	</Person>
  <Person>
    <ID>27</ID>
    <Name>Ramy Saad</Name>
    <Title>Dr</Title>
    <Job>Academic Clinical Fellow</Job>
    <Email>ramy.saad.10@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
    <ResearchInterest>
      Research Interests: Epigenomics, Nutrition, Rare Diseases
    </ResearchInterest>
    <Biography>
      Ramy is an Academic Clinical Fellow in Genetics at GOSH, with a clinical interest in rare diseases and nutrition. His research interest is the epigenetic interface between nutrients and genome-wide methylation. He is currently exploring nutrient-methylation interactions by EWAS to identify potential therapeutics or personalised diets for managing individual rare diseases.
    </Biography>
    <ImagePath>ramy.png</ImagePath>
    <GitHub></GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar>ramysaad</GoogleScholar>
    <ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
    <CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
  </Person>
  <Person>
    <ID>28</ID>
    <Name>Pilar Álvarez Jerez</Name>
    <Title>BSc</Title>
    <Job>PhD Student</Job>
    <Email>pilar.jerez.22@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
    <ResearchInterest>
      Long-read sequencing, neurodegenerative disease, genomics
    </ResearchInterest>
    <Biography>
      Pilar Alvarez Jerez is a PhD student within the long-read team at the Center for Alzheimer’s and Related Dementias (CARD), NIH and the Ryten Lab at UCL. Her current work focuses on using long read technologies to identify the role of structural variants on gene expression and methylation within neurodegenerative diseases, most notably Parkinson’s disease and Alzheimer’s disease. Before coming to NIH, Pilar got her BSc in Applied Physiology and Kinesiology from the University of Florida.
    </Biography>
    <ImagePath>pilar.png</ImagePath>
    <GitHub>pilaralv</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
    <ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
    <CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
  </Person>
  <Person>
    <ID>29</ID>
    <Name>Claire Anderson</Name>
    <Title>Dr</Title>
    <Job>Research Assistant</Job>
    <Email>claire.anderson@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
    <ResearchInterest>
      Genomics, transcriptomics, gene expression, neurodegeneration, Parkinson’s Disease, developmental neurobiology
    </ResearchInterest>
    <Biography>
      Claire is a research assistant in the Ryten lab funded by The Michael J. Fox Foundation for Parkinson’s Research and Aligning Science Across Parkinson’s (ASAP) Collaborative Research Network initiative. Claire uses long read sequencing technologies to understand the pathological mechanisms of Parkinson’s Disease.
      <br/>
      Claire did her undergraduate degree in biomedical science specialising in developmental biology in her postgraduate studies at The University of Sheffield. She then went on to work as a post-doctoral researcher at University College London.
    </Biography>
    <ImagePath>claire.png</ImagePath>
    <GitHub></GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
    <ResearchGate>Claire-Anderson-10</ResearchGate>
    <CurrentMember>N</CurrentMember>
  </Person>
  <Pet>
    <ID>30</ID>
    <Name>Nuptse and Nilo</Name>
    <Nickname>NupNup, Nups and Nilo-baby</Nickname>
    <HumanName>Claire (Nick, Iris and Otis)</HumanName>
    <ImagePath>claire_cats.png</ImagePath>
    <Bio>
      Nilo and Nuptse are brother and sister and have fallen out with each other, very much like brothers and sisters do. Nuptse loves to be around people, except when she doesn’t. Nilo loves a warm lap, radiators and the fireplace, he also loves to eat Claire’s plants. Both are fair-weather cats and only really go outside when it’s baking hot.
    </Bio>
  </Pet>
  <Person>
    <ID>31</ID>
    <Name>Hannah Macpherson</Name>
    <Title>MSc</Title>
    <Job>Phd Student</Job>
    <Email>hannah.macpherson.14@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
    <ResearchInterest>
      Genomics, transcriptomics, gene expression, neurodegeneration, Parkinson’s Disease, developmental neurobiology
    </ResearchInterest>
    <Biography>
      Hannah completed her MSci at UCL, where her Master’s project investigated proteostasis in aging C. elegans at the Institute of Healthy Aging. She has five years of experience in Long Read Sequencing, which she initially started at the Anthony Nolan Research Institute where she worked as a Research Assistant for two years. There, she did PacBio sequencing of HLA class I and class II genes with the aim to improve stem cell transplant outcomes and matching.
      <br/>
      In 2021 she moved back to UCL as a Senior Research Technician, where she lead the UCL Long Read Sequencing Service. She has worked on a wide range of projects, from de novo genomes to targeted transcriptomics, and utilising both Oxford Nanopore and PacBio technologies.
      <br/>
      In 2023 she joined the Ryten lab as a PhD student, where she will apply her knowledge of Long Read Sequencing to Parkinson’s Disease Transcriptomics.
    </Biography>
    <ImagePath>hannah.png</ImagePath>
    <GitHub>MacphersonHannah</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
    <ResearchGate>Hannah-Macpherson-3</ResearchGate>
    <CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
  </Person>
  <Pet>
    <ID>32</ID>
    <Name>Terry</Name>
    <Nickname>Tesla, Tez</Nickname>
    <HumanName>Hannah</HumanName>
    <ImagePath>terry.png</ImagePath>
    <Bio>
      Terry is a cheeky orange cat, who is extremely curious about the world but sometimes lacks basic survival skills. He is a CIS (Cat In Stem) and has previously attended the 2021 online Nanopore conference, which he fondly refers to as ‘Nanopaw’. In his spare time, he enjoys staring menacingly at squirrels, stealing pieces of uncooked spaghetti, and hiding grapes under the sofa.
    </Bio>
  </Pet>
  <Person>
    <ID>33</ID>
    <Name>Jonathan Brenton</Name>
    <Title>PhD</Title>
    <Job>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</Job>
    <Email>jonathan.brenton.14@ucl.ac.uk</Email>
    <ResearchInterest>
      Neurodegeneration; Bioinformatics; Ageing; Transcriptomics
    </ResearchInterest>
    <Biography>
      Jon is a a postdoctoral research fellow in the Ryten lab at University College London. He received a BSc in Psychology from the University of Birmingham and an MSc in Neuroscience from University College London. He also completed his PhD at University College London funded by the BBSRC LIDo PhD programme.
      The project involved the electrophysiological and transcriptomic analysis of ageing in an obesity model. His current work involves the analysis of splicing and gene expression in Parkinson’s disease patients.
    </Biography>
    <ImagePath>jon.png</ImagePath>
    <GitHub>Jbrenton191</GitHub>
    <GoogleScholar></GoogleScholar>
    <ResearchGate></ResearchGate>
    <CurrentMember>Y</CurrentMember>
  </Person>
	<Pet>
		<ID>34</ID>
		<Name>Elbereth (Elbie) and Bilbo</Name>
		<Nickname>Elbereth Gilthoniel and Bilbo Catkins</Nickname>
		<HumanName>Zhongbo (the reluctant cat parent) and family</HumanName>
		<ImagePath>elbereth.png</ImagePath>
		<Bio>
			In Zhongbo's house, two Siberian cats reign free,
			Elbie and Bilbo, as proud as can be.

			Elbie, named after an elven queen bright,
			With fur pure white, she purrs through the night.
			A bossy young feline, she's sharp and she's bold,
			Ruling the house with a heart made of gold.

			Bilbo, the adventurer, loves to explore,
			Climbing up trees but getting stuck more!
			With a heart full of courage and whiskers so neat,
			He's always in search of a high-up retreat.

		</Bio>
	</Pet>
</TeamMembers>